It's that during the first 3-4 days, the oocyte that
这是因为在最初的3-4天里，您看到的卵母细胞，
you see there, it's not called an oocyte, it's now called a zygote.
它不叫卵母细胞，现在它被称为受精卵。
But now there's something very important, because it's an algorithm that will repeat
但现在有一个非常重要的事情，因为这是一个将在整个发育过程中重复出现的算法。
throughout development.
在整个发育过程中。
I asked you to remember one thing, to understand the movements well,
我曾要求你们记住一件事，要很好地理解运动，
the notion of growth.
生长的概念。
of developmental movements in growth.
生长中的发育运动。
Now, I'm going to ask you to understand this process well.
现在，我将要求你们很好地理解这个过程。
So we have another image of polarity.
所以我们有另一幅极性的图像。
These first two life cells will now divide
这两个最初的生命细胞现在将分裂
extremely quickly and more and more to form a cluster of
以极快的速度，并且越来越快，形成一团
small cells.
小细胞。
But these first two life cells respond to a polarity,
但这两个最初的生命细胞响应着一种极性，
that means they won't divide.
这意味着它们不会分裂。
divided at the beginning at the same speed.
最初以相同的速度分裂。
And the fact that they don't divide
而它们不分裂的事实
at the same speed, it responds
以相同的速度，这再次响应了
again to polarity.
极性。
Every time I have cell division,
每次细胞分裂时，
I have an increase in my membrane
我的细胞膜会增加
and I have a loss of fluid outside.
并且我会有一些液体流失到外面。
I have a small exudate.
我有一些小的渗出物。
So, what will it do?
那么，它会做什么呢？
It will create
它会创造
a mass of cells with,
一团细胞，旁边，
next to it, overall,
总的来说，
a first small fluid cavity
第一个小的液腔
that will appear.
将会出现。
And in
并且在
the first instance, during the first few days, in fact, it multiplies, but the
最初，在最初的几天里，实际上，它在增殖，但整个
whole
整体
does not grow. And so, for a certain time, as I have an information of
并没有长大。因此，在一段时间内，由于我有一个增殖的信息
multiplication
增殖
and a small loss of water, I have an overall increase in my membrane and an overall
和少量失水，我的细胞膜整体增加，我的细胞整体增加，在一个受限的空间内。这意味着什么？这意味着我的整体新陈代谢增加，或者换句话说，我的能量增加。
increase in my cells, in a confined space. What does that mean? That I have an increase
我的细胞整体增加，在一个受限的空间内。这意味着什么？这意味着我的整体新陈代谢增加，或者换句话说，我的能量增加。
in my overall metabolism that increases, or in other words, I have an increase
我的整体新陈代谢增加，或者换句话说，我的能量增加。
in energy.
一种能量。
potentials that are developing.
潜在的正在发展。
You didn't understand everything, I'll repeat.
你们没有完全理解，我再重复一遍。
Initially,
最初，
you see the image,
你看到图片了，
I have my first two
我有我的前两个
life cells in a confined space
生命细胞在一个受限的空间里
of a membrane called
一个我们称之为
the zona pellucida.
卵黄膜的膜。
Inside, I find myself
在那里，我发现自己
with the first two cells.
和前两个细胞在一起。
What do both of them have?
它们两个，它们有什么？
We observe that each of them has
我们发现它们每个
a nucleus inside.
内部都有一个细胞核。
Never
从不
without...
没有...
They are always eccentric, contained in a plane.
它们总是偏心的，包含在一个平面中。
Cell A and cell B.
细胞A和细胞B。
Well, depending on the polarity, one that is closer in its metabolic field,
那么，根据极性，其中一个在其代谢场中更接近的，
will divide, so divide, a little faster
会分裂，所以分裂得稍微快一点
than that one.
比那个。
We observe that it will form this.
我们发现它会形成这个。
A little faster.
快一点。
Each time I have a division or cellular cleavage, I
每次我有一个细胞分裂或卵裂，我
have an overall increase in the length of my membrane,
的膜长度会整体增加，
so more surface area for exchange, and
所以有更多的交换表面，并且
an overall increase compared to this one.
相对于这个，整体增加。
And in addition, I have an overall increase compared to this one.
此外，相对于这个，我有一个整体的增加。
on the side, an exudate, a little fluid that leaves,
在侧面，渗出物，一些液体流出，
which will be here a little more than a little
它会在这里多一点，而不是一点点
fluid that appears. Now, I'm going to show you a short film
液体出现。现在，我将向您展示一个短片
that shows us this
它向我们展示了这种
asymmetric division, because if it was really like we see in the little
不对称分裂，因为如果它真的像我们在小
things
东西中看到的那样
that we've always believed, at the same time, it doesn't happen
一直让我们相信的，同时，它不会
like that, it happens
那样发生，它会发生
In fact, it's just an expression of polarity.
事实上，这只是极性的一种表达。
What makes it go faster on one side than the other?
是什么让它在一侧比在另一侧更快？
It's not centered in the nucleus.
它不以细胞核为中心。
There is a nucleus that is not, even exactly, there is one that is closer to a metabolic field.
有一个细胞核不是，甚至不完全是，有一个更接近代谢场。
It is the one that will be closest to give the metabolic field.
它将是离代谢场最近的那个。
So here, we see these first cells.
所以在这里，我们看到了这些最初的细胞。
And we'll see here.
我们在这里会看到。
Oops, you see?
瞧，你看到了吗？
Okay.
好的。
and then the other will follow
然后另一个会跟着
after
之后
and it's never similar
而且它们从不相似
that means that in the body
这意味着在身体里
in life there is no
在生命中不存在
symmetry
对称
but there is
但存在
harmony
和谐
so initially
所以一开始
it's not
它不是
in the middle like that, I have two cells, it's powerful, capacity
中间像这样，我有两个细胞，这很强大，有能力
for exchange, there are only two nuclei,
进行交换，只有两个细胞核，
and then three cells, three nuclei, so
然后是三个细胞，三个细胞核，所以
greater metabolic exchange force,
代谢交换力更强，
because that, if I take a cell and put its
因为这个，如果我取一个细胞，然后把它的
nucleus here,
细胞核放在这里，
well here, this potential energy here, it's a metabolic potential.
那么这里，这里的能量潜力，是一个代谢潜力。
it's a force of exchange, okay, it's powerful here, less
这是一种交换力，好的，这里很强大，这里
strong here, less strong here, much stronger here, okay, I will always
不那么强，这里不那么强，这里强得多，好的，我总是会
cleave like that, change myself, it's an important door, okay, now, imagine
像这样分裂，改变自己，这是一个重要的门户，好的，现在，想象一下
that I am in the same space,
我处于同一个空间，
because for 3-4 days, the whole thing
因为在3-4天内，整体会
divides more and more, but does not...
不断分裂，但不会...
I'm not growing.
我没有长大。
At a given moment, I divide and it's as if, you imagine, I
在某个时刻，我分裂了，就好像，你想象一下，我
will mimic a power.
会模仿一种力量。
Suddenly, it becomes internal like you have.
突然之间，它变得内在，就像你一样。
A mass of metabolic energy ready to explode,
一个代谢能量团块，随时准备爆发，
to come out, to go in search of new trophic forces.
出来，去寻找新的营养力。
Initially, I have like an energy, a mass energy, a
一开始，我有一种能量，一种质量能量，一种
potential energy that builds up, a metabolic power that becomes
正在形成的势能，一种正在形成的非常非常强大的代谢力，
very very strong, that concentrates for three days.
它在三天内集中起来。
That's a lot for three days.
三天时间很长。
I reach a sufficient concentration to around the 3rd,
我达到了足够的浓度，以便在大约第3、
4th day to do what is called a hatching phenomenon.
第4天发生我们所说的孵化现象。
That means that the cell that is enclosed, the whole is enclosed in a tissue, all
这意味着被包裹的细胞，整体被包裹在一个组织中，突然之间
of a sudden the force is sufficient for there to be a rupture
力量足够大，可以发生破裂
and I will go into my tube to go towards
然后我将进入我的输卵管，前往
the implantation site.
着床地点。
At that moment, we have what is called the hatching phenomenon.
在那一刻，我们有所谓的孵化现象。
But just before this hatching phenomenon, in this
但在孵化现象发生之前，在这一层中，
layer, what did I tell you?
我告诉了你们什么？
Every time there is cell division, there is an overall increase in
每次细胞分裂，我的膜尺寸都会整体增加，
the size of my membrane,
我的膜尺寸会整体增加，
an increase in the number of cells, therefore a metabolic increase, an increase in force,
细胞数量增加，因此新陈代谢增加，力量增加，
a power,
一种力量，
and in addition, there is an exudate.
此外，还有渗出物。
And the very first cavity that will appear, what does the water do?
第一个出现的腔体，水，它做了什么？
It joins together, it forms a small cavity here.
它汇合在一起，在这里形成一个小腔体。
And what is this small cavity called?
这个小腔体叫什么？
It is the first fluid cavity of the body.
这是身体的第一个液腔。
But in fact, it will be called the blastocoel.
但实际上，它将被称为胚泡腔。
And typologically, what does that mean?
从类型学上讲，这意味着什么？
Blastocoel, the germ of the coelom.
胚泡腔，天堂的萌芽。
And you will see that this small cavity, we will see later,
你们会看到，这个小腔体，我们稍后会看到，
of great importance
非常重要
in the future cavity
在未来的腔体中
peritoneal.
腹膜。
I will have what is called a phenomenon
我将有所谓的现象
of hatching.
孵化。
Initially, if I draw the first diagram,
最初，如果我画第一个图，
I have many cells,
我有很多细胞，
and I have a cavity,
我有一个腔体，
and this cavity is always
这个腔体总是
eccentric. Why?
偏心的。为什么？
It is also the expression of a global polarity.
这也是整体极性的一种表达。
And the fact that there is this eccentric phenomenon, it will create a concentration
偏心现象的存在，会在一个极点形成细胞的集中，
of cells in one pole,
在一个极点形成细胞的集中，
which is called the pole, you have the animal poles and the vegetal pole, the pole of
我们称之为极点，你们有动物极和植物极，同化极。
assimilation.
同化。
A concentration of cells here.
这里细胞集中。
Lots of cells.
很多细胞。
And here, I have less.
而这里，我这里细胞较少。
First cavity here, you see, that appears.
第一个腔体在这里出现，你看到了吗？
It's a cellular exudate in a space,
这是细胞渗出物在一个空间中，
here, and between this level and this level, there
在这里，在这个层面和这个层面之间，
is the phenomenon of hatching.
存在孵化现象。
That means that the membrane that is here around can no longer maintain the thing.
这意味着周围的膜无法再维持这个东西。
Now, it's too strong, there's a rupture, and we see that
现在，它太强了，发生了破裂，我们看到
there's a rupture here, and it starts to leave and come out.
这里有一个破裂，它开始离开并出来。
The passage between this first cavity
这个第一腔之间的通道
with this exudate that forms the first cavity
与形成第一腔的渗出物
which is called the blastocoel
我们称之为胚泡
will grow.
会变大。
The difference between here and there
这里和那里的区别
is that it's much bigger.
是它大得多。
Because I have
因为我
come out of the membrane.
离开了膜。
Remember, initially, for 3 days
请记住，最初的3天里
the embryo does not grow.
胚胎不生长。
Well, the thing doesn't grow,
总之，那个东西不生长，
it always stays like that.
它总是保持这样。
Except that inside,
除非在里面，
there is a power.
有一种力量。
And then,
然后，
at a given moment, the tissue that surrounds me, there is a rupture, and boom, there
在某个时刻，包围我的组织破裂了，然后，
is hatching,
孵化发生了，
I leave my egg, somewhere, and I find myself in this external environment, and
我离开了我的卵子，在某种程度上，我发现自己处于这个外部环境中，并且
in
在这个
this external environment, very quickly, I organize myself into a
外部环境中，我很快组织成一个
concentrated zone of cells and a
细胞的集中区域和一个
And it's always the same image, it's the blastocoel, but this time, which
这仍然是同一个图像，它是胚泡，但这次它
will
将
become with what is called...
与我们所说的...
An embryonic pole, that is to say a concentration of cells
一个胚胎极，也就是说，细胞的浓度
more important on one side than on the other.
在一侧比在另一侧更重要。
And this pole, what is it? It's an assimilation pole.
这个极是什么？它是一个同化极。
Assimilate, it seeks to take the table.
同化，它试图占据桌面。